Guide to the Washington Office on Latin America Records, 1962-2020 and undated, bulk 1974-2005; 1962-ongoing RL.01401
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oversize Material, 1971-2000 and undated, 7 boxes
  - Geographic Series
    - Brazil
      - Boletim Nacional, 1991-1993 (Box 417)
      - Land reform files and printed material, 1995, undated (Box 417)
    - Chile
      - Advertisements and headlines, 1971-1972, undated (Box 417)
      - American publications, 1973-1974 (Box 417)
      - Chile-recent, 1974-1976, undated (Box 417)
      - Chile Hoy, 1972-1973 (Box 418-419)
      - Clippings, 1972-1976, undated, 7 folders (Box 417)
      - El Mercurio, 1974, 4 folders (Box 420)
      - Latin American clippings, 1973, undated (Box 420)
      - Political posters, undated (Box 434)
      - Political posters and newspaper advertisements, 1972-1974, undated (Box 420)
      - Solidaridad, 1977-1983 (Box 421)
      - Spanish language publications, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 420)
      - U.S.-Chile Letelier assassination files, 1974-1976, undated (Box 420)
      - VEA, 1973 (Box 421)
      - Unsorted serials, 1971-1973, undated (Box 421)
      - Washington Post section, 2000 (Box 422)
    - Cuba
      - Newspapers and posters, 1995-1996, undated (Box 434)
    - Costa Rica
      - Tico Times, 1988 Dec., 1991 Oct. (Box 422)
    - El Salvador
      - Diario Latino, 1993 (Box 422)
    - Guatemala
      - CUC [Comite de Unidad Campesina], 1980 (Box 420)
      - AEU [Asociación de Estudiantes Universitarios], 1988-1989 (Box 420)
      - Siglo News, 2000 (Box 422)
    - Haiti
      - Haiti en Marche, 1997 (Box 422)
    - Honduras
      - Baltimore Sun section, 1995 (Box 422)
    - Mexico
      - La Journada, 1997 (Box 422)
    - Panama
      - Political posters, undated (Box 434)
    - Perú
      - Expresso sections, 1993 (Box 422)
  - Initiatives and Activities Series
    - Hurricane Mitch
      - Transformando la Reconstrucción, 1999-2000 (Box 422)
    - Rights and Development
      - Emerging Markets, 1998 Mar. 15-16 (Box 422)
      - Bio-Bio dam (Chile), 1994 (Box 420)
- Accession (2010-0069), 10 boxes
  Materials from programs in Haiti, Guatemala, Colombia, and Mexico, and development files from the organization. Materials have not been described or arranged beyond their original condition. Folder titles reflect the titles assigned by WOLA staff.
  - Fundraising
    - Board meeting, April 2007 (Box 423)
    - Carol Pitchersky (Box 423)
    - MOTT Charitable Trust, 2002 (Box 423)
    - MOTT Charitable Trust, 2001 (Box 423)
    - Stewart Mott charitable trust (Box 423)
    - Finn, OMI, Seamus (Box 423)
    - Moriah interim 2, September 2001 (Box 423)
    - Merck fund (Box 423)
    - Merck, January 2002 (Box 423)
    - Merck general support, 2002 (Box 423)
    - Moriah fund correspondence (Box 423)
    - Ford Mexico, Mitch, 2001-2002 (Box 423)
    - General Service Foundation, general support 2001-2002 (Box 423)
    - General Service Foundation, Columbia Monitoring Project, 2001-2002 (Box 423)
    - Hewlett Foundation (Box 423)
    - Merck general support, 2001 (Box 423)
    - Ford general support, 1995-1997 (Box 423)
    - Ford democracy and economic reform, 2000-2001 (Box 423)
    - Ford (Box 423)
    - C.S. Fund correspondence (Box 423)
    - Drug Policy Foundation correspondence (Box 423)
    - Ford, Central America Advocacy Training Program, 1999-2000 (Box 423)
    - Liz Claiborne Foundation, Juarez delegation (Box 423)
    - Compton Foundation correspondence (Box 423)
    - United States Institute of Peace, Public Security Reform, 2002 (Box 423)
    - United States Institute of Peace, Colombia, 2001 (Box 423)
    - United States Institute of Peace, 2003 (Box 423)
    - Christopher Reynolds correspondence (Box 423)
    - Christopher Reynolds, 2002 (Box 423)
    - Daniele Agostino, 2003 (Box 423)
    - Agostino correspondence (Box 423)
    - Peace Development Fund, Lippincott Foundation, 2003 (Box 423)
    - Angelica Foundation Press (Box 423)
    - Angelica, 2002 (Box 423)
    - Angelica Foundation correspondence (Box 423)
    - Banyan Tree correspondence (Box 423)
    - Boehm correspondence and notes (Box 423)
    - Careth correspondence (Box 423)
    - Careth proposals and reports (Box 423)
    - Threshold Foundation (Box 423)
    - Peace Development Fund (Box 423)
    - Open Society Institute Drugs and Democracy (Box 423)
    - Arca Foundation correspondence (Box 423)
  - Financials and training programs
    - Funding: Prodeca Media Project planning meeting, November 2001 (Box 424)
    - Prodeca Media Project (Box 424)
    - Prodeca, 1998-1999 (Box 424)
    - Prodeca six month report, 1997-1998 (Box 424)
    - Prodeca proposal 1997-1998 (Box 424)
    - Reebok (Box 424)
    - Profed (Box 424)
    - Public Welfare Foundation (Box 424)
    - Funding: SOROS, external evaluation, 2001 (Box 424)
    - SOROS, 2002-2003 (Box 424)
    - Funding: SOROS proposal, 2002-2003 (Box 424)
    - SOROS proposal, 1999-2002 (Box 424)
    - Summit Foundation (Box 424)
    - Funding: TROCAIRE (Box 424)
    - Funding: UNDP, Guatemala (Box 424)
    - Funding: UNDP, El Salvador (Box 424)
    - UNDP project (Box 424)
    - Funding: UNIFEM (Box 424)
    - Funding: United Methodist (Box 424)
    - Funding: USCC (Box 424)
    - Winston proposal (Box 424)
    - WOLA advocacy plan, 1995-1996 (Box 424)
    - Advocacy planning day, WOLA (Box 424)
    - Preliminary ideas, WOLA (Box 424)
    - Matriz de Planificacion, 1999 (Box 424)
    - Advocacy Training Program (ATP) training, 2002 (Box 424)
    - CEDPA reports (Box 424)
    - ATP training, Guatemala workshop, 2001 (Box 424)
    - ATP training, Guatemala, Calas (Box 424)
    - ATP training, 2001 (Box 424)
    - CAII workshop, 1997-1999 (Box 424)
    - Training: indigenous (Box 424)
    - Training: women, El Salvador (Box 424)
    - El Salvador: COMURES (Box 424)
    - USA: women, law, and development (Box 424)
    - Intermon (Box 424)
    - Mexíco: International HIV/AIDS Alliance (Box 424)
    - ATP: advocacy training workshop, 2001 (Box 424)
    - Case study: train community, leaders in Perú (Box 424)
    - Colombia: PDPMM (Box 424)
    - Costa Rica: CEDARENA (Box 424)
    - USA: CARE (Box 424)
    - Training: violence against women workshop follow-up (Box 424)
    - Training: violence against women workshop memoria (Box 424)
    - Training: violence against women workshop participants (Box 424)
    - Training: violence against women workshop proposal (Box 424)
    - ATP: Urban Institute meeting (Box 424)
    - Training: PRESS workshops (Box 424)
    - Workshop on negotiation (Box 424)
    - Training: Antigua meeting participants, 2000 (Box 424)
  - Training programs, Mexico FOIA
    - Training: Antigua meeting questionnaires, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Training: Antigua meeting memoria, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Training: Antigua meeting matrix, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Advocacy Learning Initiative (Box 425)
    - ATP: Forum-Snd Pasantia (Box 425)
    - Internship (Box 425)
    - Pasantias: participants, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Training: Pasantias (Box 425)
    - Training workshops, 1995-1998 (Box 425)
    - Training templates (Box 425)
    - Training: El Salvador (Box 425)
    - ATP training: Honduras (Box 425)
    - Delegation: Convergencia de Mujeres, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Training: Honduras, Interforos-Centro (Box 425)
    - Informe: CENTRACAP and COALM (Box 425)
    - ATP training: Honduras, ASONOG (Box 425)
    - ATP: brochure (Box 425)
    - PI materials and method (Box 425)
    - Training: Nicaragua, general (Box 425)
    - Training: Nicaragua, work plan (Box 425)
    - Training: Nicaragua, BILWI, 2000 (Box 425)
    - ATP training: Nicaragua, 2002 (Box 425)
    - ATP training: Nicaragua, taller diagnostico (Box 425)
    - Ma Elena Avadra (Box 425)
    - Hivos Report, 2001 (Box 425)
    - ATP training: learning grant proposal, 2003 (Box 425)
    - ATP: CEDPA proposal to PRODECA, 2003 (Box 425)
    - POA, 2000 (Box 425)
    - ATP: plan estrategico, 2000-2002 (Box 425)
    - Training workshop reports (Box 425)
    - Training: Antigua meeting follow-up, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Training: public security (Box 425)
    - El Salvador: CACH (Box 425)
    - Training: volunteers (Box 425)
    - Training taller, 2000 (Box 425)
    - Memo: capacity building (Box 425)
    - Training: counterparts (Box 425)
    - Training: calendar, 1997 (Box 425)
    - Training: calendar, 2000-2001 (Box 425)
    - Training: calendar, 1999-2000 (Box 425)
    - ATP: accompaniment strategy (Box 425)
    - Training: general (Box 425)
    - Training: accompaniment reports by WOLA trainers (Box 425)
    - ATP: Informe de Actividades, 2001 (Box 425)
    - Training: informes mensuales, Susan Peacock (Box 425)
    - Training: informes, format (Box 425)
    - Training: POA documents, 2001 (Box 425)
    - Trade and IFI work (Box 425)
    - National police (Box 425)
    - Police/justice system corruption (Box 425)
    - DF police (Box 425)
    - Citizen participation (Box 425)
    - National government (Box 425)
    - DF government (Box 425)
    - WOLA DMN (Box 425)
    - Military justice (Box 425)
    - Recommendation Costeño, 2004 (Box 425)
    - Recommendation grants, 2004 (Box 425)
    - Quirós y acosta (Box 425)
    - SSP FOIA (Box 425)
    - RGR FOIA (Box 425)
    - Marina FOIA (Box 425)
    - Appeals Sedena (Box 425)
    - SSP appeals (Box 425)
    - Military justice, 2004 (Box 425)
    - Clips about FOIA (Box 425)
    - Sedena FOIA, general (Box 425)
    - Mexico Sedena budget (Box 425)
    - Sedena marina (Box 425)
    - Sedena Mexico (Box 425)
    - Analysis of FOIA response (Box 425)
  - Mexico FOIA, Violence against Women
    - NGO FOIA working group (Box 426)
    - Mexico violence clippings (Box 426)
    - WOLA, FOIA, US-Mexico (2 folders) (Box 426)
    - Drugs, Mexico (2 folders) (Box 426)
    - Mexico: police, military, drugs (Box 426)
    - FOIA-LF (Box 426)
    - Juarez background (Box 426)
    - Guatemala VAW (Box 426)
    - Chimalhuacan, EDOMEX (Box 426)
    - Ley de violencia contra la mujer (Box 426)
    - Estados, Mexico (Box 426)
    - Juarez background (Box 426)
    - Meeting requests (Box 426)
    - Julia Monarrez (Box 426)
    - Justicia para nuestras hijas (Box 426)
    - Murdered names (Box 426)
    - Casa amiga (Box 426)
    - Casa juvenil (Box 426)
    - CFO (Box 426)
    - CETLAC (Box 426)
    - Gender violence (Box 426)
    - Mexico press, general Juarez (Box 426)
    - Mexico press, AI report (Box 426)
    - Women's rights (Box 426)
    - Maquilas (Box 426)
    - CNDH report, Juarez (Box 426)
    - Amnesty International, Juarez (Box 426)
    - CEDAW report on Juarez (Box 426)
    - Report on victims in Juarez (Box 426)
    - Morfin/Lopez Urbina, first informe (Box 426)
    - Report on cuidad Juarez (Box 426)
    - Juarez reprints (Box 426)
    - FBI and Juarez (Box 426)
  - Violence against Women; Haiti
    - Articles VS press (Box 427)
    - Alcoa (Box 427)
    - Visteon (Box 427)
    - Delphi (Box 427)
    - RCA Thompson (Box 427)
    - Johnson controls (Box 427)
    - Philips (Box 427)
    - Johnson & Johnson (Box 427)
    - AI-WOLA business and HR (Box 427)
    - Juarez clips (Box 427)
    - Image: CJ business (Box 427)
    - Juarez sp clips, general (Box 427)
    - Juarez US press (Box 427)
    - Patricia Gonzalez (Box 427)
    - Istanbul protocol (Box 427)
    - Mexico government talking points (Box 427)
    - Letters regarding human rights concerns (Box 427)
    - Drugs: drugs and police force, U.S. concerns (Box 427)
    - Politicization of PNH (Box 427)
    - Initial observation of police: UN police missions and reports (Box 427)
    - General police (PNH) articles (Box 427)
    - Inspector generale (IG): formal human rights complaints, PNH records (Box 427)
    - Institutional development: administration, equipment, leadership, general operations, PNH personnel (2 folders) (Box 427)
    - U.S. Policy: financial assistance, interventions, negotiations, statements/press releases (Box 427)
    - Crime/political violence (Box 427)
    - U.S. State Department country reports, 1998-2000 (Box 427)
    - Newsletters/pamphlets (Box 427)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 427)
    - Letters (Box 427)
    - UN General Assembly (Box 427)
    - MICIVIH-human rights/government record (Box 427)
    - Press releases (Box 427)
    - OAS/UN mission, Haiti press releases, May-July 1994 (Box 427)
    - OAS/UN mission, Haiti press releases, February-April 1994 (Box 427)
    - OAS/UN mission, Haiti press releases, November-January 1993/1994 (Box 427)
    - OAS/UN mission, Haiti press releases, August-October 1993 (Box 427)
    - Extra information (Box 427)
    - OAS/UN mission, Haiti press releases, May-July 1993 (Box 427)
    - OAS/UN mission, Haiti press releases, February-April 1993 (Box 427)
    - Haiti: MICIVIH, January-June judicial reform report, 1994 (Box 427)
    - Files to be read (now in French) (Box 427)
    - MICIVIH-MINUGUA (Box 427)
    - Haiti: OAS missions UN (Box 427)
    - OAS resolution 806, January 2002 (Box 427)
    - Haiti elections (Box 427)
    - Haiti, general (Box 427)
    - ICG reports, Haiti (Box 427)
  - Haiti, Old proposals
    - Haiti correspondence/memos (Box 428)
    - Haiti news clippings (Box 428)
    - Haiti materials (6 folders) (Box 428)
    - Funding: PCS (Box 428)
    - Funding: Peace Development Fund (Box 428)
    - Public Welfare Foundation (Box 428)
    - OXFAM-Nicaragua (Box 428)
    - OXFAM/UK (Box 428)
    - NOVIB (Box 428)
    - Open Society Institute (Box 428)
    - Moriah - ATP, 1999-2000 (Box 428)
    - Funding: Moriah fund, ATP, 1998-2000 (Box 428)
    - Funding: Moriah fund, general (Box 428)
    - Funding: Moriah fund: grant, May 2002, April 2003 (Box 428)
    - Funding: Moriah Fund: ATP, May 2000, April 2002 (Box 428)
    - Funding: Merck fund (Box 428)
    - Funding: Ms. Foundation (Box 428)
    - Funding: Liz Claiborne (Box 428)
    - KEPA-Finlandia, Nicaragua (Box 428)
    - Funding: Kellogg (Box 428)
    - International foundation (Box 428)
    - IDEX (Box 428)
    - Intermon proposal (Box 428)
    - IBIS-dinamarca (Box 428)
    - Funding: HIVOS, 2002-2004 (Box 428)
    - HIVOS, 1999-2001 (Box 428)
    - HELVETAS (Box 428)
    - Funding: Greenville (Box 428)
    - Funding: Global Fund for Women (Box 428)
    - Funding: Common Global Ministries Board (Box 428)
    - Funding: Global Service Foundation (Box 428)
    - Ford Advocacy Proposal, 1996-1998 (Box 428)
    - Ford conference: bios (Box 428)
    - Funding: Ford, 2001 (Box 428)
    - Ford renewal, 1999-2000 (Box 428)
    - Ebert Foundation correspondence (Box 428)
    - Funding: Dominican Sisters (Box 428)
    - Diakonia-taller (Box 428)
    - Funding: Diakonia (Box 428)
    - Diakonia Convenio, 1998 (Box 428)
    - Diakonia, 1999 (Box 428)
    - CRS, 1999-2001 (Box 428)
    - CRS Convenio, 1997 (Box 428)
    - Daniel Agostino (Box 428)
    - CRS (Box 428)
    - CRS, comunicaciones (Box 428)
    - CRS report, 2001 (Box 428)
  - OAS monitoring files
    - Human rights clips, 2002 (Box 429)
    - United Nations clips, 2002 (Box 429)
    - United Nations clips, 1996 (Box 429)
    - United Nations, 1996 (Box 429)
    - UN council for a livable word (Box 429)
    - UN miscellaneous (Box 429)
    - UN at 50 years old clips (Box 429)
    - UN HR commission (Box 429)
    - UN high commissioner for refugees (Box 429)
    - International criminal court (Box 429)
    - Robert Goldman (Box 429)
    - UN human rights newsletter (Box 429)
    - UNESCO 40th anniversary, 1988 (Box 429)
    - US and the OAS (Box 429)
    - OAS, general (Box 429)
    - OAS Gaviria (Box 429)
    - OAS election monitoring (Box 429)
    - Inter-American Commission of Human Rights (Box 429)
    - IACHR "reforms" (Box 429)
    - Inter-American Court of Human Rights (Box 429)
    - OAS Democracy Unit (Box 429)
    - ZALAQUETT project (Box 429)
    - Issue: amnesties (Box 429)
    - Children's rights (Box 429)
    - Human rights, general (Box 429)
    - HR conditionality on economic aid (Box 429)
    - HR political violence, use of force, rule of law (Box 429)
    - Human rights and intervention (Box 429)
    - Economic Sanctions (Box 429)
  - Old proposals, Columbia
    - ATP: CIPA Convenio (Box 430)
    - Funding: CRINF (Box 430)
    - Funding: Children's Haven (Box 430)
    - CA II proposal and convenio (Box 430)
    - ATP: fundraising, Banyan Tree, final report, 2000-2002 (Box 430)
    - Banyan Tree, 2000 (Box 430)
    - Banyan Tree, 1999 (Box 430)
    - Funding: Banyan Tree, 1997-1999 (Box 430)
    - Action aid (Box 430)
    - Funding: Agostino (Box 430)
    - Banyan Tree: capacity building colloquium, December 2001 (Box 430)
    - Presupuesto BTF, 2001 (Box 430)
    - Funding: Banyan Tree, 2000-2002 (Box 430)
    - Regional advocacy proposal (Box 430)
    - Proposals (Box 430)
    - ATP-TEN proposal, 1995 (Box 430)
    - Colombia, miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box 430)
    - OSAID Colombia (Box 430)
    - South Sobre Bank, 1994 (Box 430)
    - Conditions, November 2004 (Box 430)
    - Reunion Colombian working groups (Box 430)
    - 660 reforms (Box 430)
    - Planning process (Box 430)
    - Colombia work, strategy (Box 430)
    - Plan, Colombia (Box 430)
    - Human rights reports (Box 430)
    - Colombia news (Box 430)
    - Colombia correspondence (Box 430)
    - Colombia materials (4 folders) (Box 430)
  - Colombia, Guatemala
    - Colombia materials (4 folders) (Box 431)
    - Frank's visit, September 2001 (Box 431)
    - Guatemala rural development report (Box 431)
    - Guatemala rural development WOLA documents (Box 431)
    - Guatemala rural development Congress report (Box 431)
    - Guatemala: land issues (Box 431)
    - Guatemala: labor review (Box 431)
    - Guatemala: economy (Box 431)
    - WOLA-US leap GSP review, 2004 (Box 431)
    - Guatemala: economy, CAFTA protests WOLA, March 2005 (2 folders) (Box 431)
    - Guatemala: land issues, June 2004 accords (Box 431)
    - Rural development, Maria Lourdes case (Box 431)
    - Land issues, evictions (Box 431)
    - Indigenous case, Corozo (Box 431)
    - Guatemala cases (Box 431)
    - Myrna Mack trial, September 2002 (Box 431)
    - Myrna Mack trial updates, September 2002 (Box 431)
    - Cases: Myrna Mack appeals (Box 431)
    - Mining: Madre Selva document (Box 431)
    - Mining estor (Box 431)
    - Mack trial, press work (Box 431)
    - Dear colleague mack, 2003 (Box 431)
    - Myrna Mack case sentence (Box 431)
    - Mack news (Box 431)
    - Myrna Mack trial press coverage (Box 431)
    - Case: Myrna Mack (Box 431)
    - Mack trial (Box 431)
    - Genocide cases (Box 431)
    - Genocide cases: Stratagem meeting (Box 431)
    - Guatemala Case: Gerard (Box 431)
    - Case: Dos Erres, 1982 (Box 431)
    - Dos Erres, 2005 (Box 431)
    - Cases: FAFT, 2005 (Box 431)
    - Dear colleague Omppa protest, 2005 (Box 431)
    - Security PN files (Box 431)
    - Guatemala, miscellaneous (Box 431)
    - Guatemala observation project (Box 431)
  - Guatemala
    - Elections, 2003, campaign scandal (Box 432)
    - Elections, 2003, NGO statements (Box 432)
    - Elections, 1999 (Box 432)
    - Census, 2002 (Box 432)
    - Tribuno Supremo Electoral (Box 432)
    - Elections, 2003, PDH observation (Box 432)
    - Elections, 2003, press coverage (Box 432)
    - Elections, November 2003 (Box 432)
    - Chixoy case (Box 432)
    - Chixoy Dam (Box 432)
    - Chixoy Dam, 2005 (Box 432)
    - Chixoy Dam, miscellaneous (Box 432)
    - Choi and Shin, 2001 (Box 432)
    - Rios case (Box 432)
    - Statements by Civil Society, February 2000 (Box 432)
    - GOG documents, February 2002 (Box 432)
    - CG press, February 2002 (Box 432)
    - Matriz de Seguimiento (Box 432)
- Accession (2012-0016), 1 box
  Contains publications and reports from The Washington Office on Latin America as well as other publications. Most deal with human rights issues in Latin America in the late 1970s and early 1980s and U.S. policies in the region. Documents are organized alphabetically.
  - Central America 1981, Rep. Gerry E. Studds to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1981 Feb. (Box 433)
  - Chile - The Ethics of Responsibility, Human Rights: Truth and Reconciliation in Chile, The Washington Office on Latin America, 1991 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Attack on schools and teachers, 1980 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Background information, 1980 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - History and Motivations of U.S. Involvement in the Control of the Peasant Movement, 1970-1980, circa 1980 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Land Reform 1980-1981, Oxfam, 1980 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Maryknoll Sisters, 1980 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Statement of Dr. Leograde before the Subcommittee on Inter-American Affairs, Committee on Foreign Affairs, U.S. House of Representatives, 1981 March 5 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Statement of Representatives Gerry Studds, Barbara Mikulski, and Robert Edgar, Before the Foreign Operations Subcommittee, House Committee on Appropriations, 1981 February 25 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Suggested Actions for Religious Organizations in their Work with the Media, 1981 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Unnamed page of document, Leftists end occupation in El Salvador, undated (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - U.S. military aid, 1980 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - U.S. military aid, 1980-1982 (Box 433)
  - El Salvador - Various publications, 1978-1998, Majority 1978-1983. (Box 433)
  - Guatemala - Right-wing military, 1979-1983 (Box 433)
  - Guatemala - The Lost Opportunity, Some Reflections on the Human Rights Situation 1986-88, Norton, Reggie, 1988 (Box 433)
  - Human Rights and the U.S. National Interest, Buergenthal, Thomas, 1981 (Box 433)
  - Human Rights Education and Training in US Policy Toward Latin America, The Washington Office on Latin America, 1992 June (Box 433)
  - Human rights NGO publications, 1977-1983 (Box 433)
  - Human Rights Working Group, 1981 (Box 433)
  - National Security Doctrine and Human Rights in Latin America: The Southern Cone, Crahan, Margaret E., 1980 March (Box 433)
  - News from Washington Office on Latin America, 1979-1983 (Box 433)
  - Nicaragua - US policy, 1979-1982 (Box 433)
  - The State and the Individual in Latin America: Some Implications for Human Rights, 1979 Oct. (Box 433)
  - The Role of International Non-Governmental Organizations in Promoting Human Rights, Coleman, John A., 1979 Oct. (Box 433)
  - Unfinished Human Rights Agenda, 1980 Jan. (Box 433)
  - The United States and the Caribbean Basin, Interamerican Policy Group, 1980 June (Box 433)
  - Update, The Washington Office on Latin America, 1978-1981 (Box 433)
  - Uruguay, 1975-1986 (Box 433)
  - Uruguay after the Plebiscite: Prospects for Democracy, The Washington Office on Latin America and American University Law School's International Law Program, 1981 June (Box 433)
  - Uruguay - Convergencia Democratica, 1980-1982 (Box 433)
- Accession (2013-0053), 39 boxes
  - Citizen Security Program, 1991-2007
    Contains files of Adriana Beltran and Susan Peacock. The contents primarily focus on Guatemala and human rights issues, particularly violence against women (VAW). Materials include correspondence, reports, presentations, training documents, and AV materials. Folders are organized alphabetically.
    - III Consulta Internacional Sobre Cooperacion, 1991 (Box 473)
    - 502B Debate (Box 473)
    - Advocacy: Allison Hillman Report (Box 473)
    - ARMS trade/control (Box 473)
    - ATP Training Materials: Afinacion de Una Propuesta (Box 473)
    - Confronting Conflict, Abuse, and Exclusion, Proposal for the Ford Foundation, n.d. (Box 473)
    - Escuela Campesina, 2001 (Box 473)
    - Family Violence Prevention Fund: International Domestic Violence (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: AMVA-CICAM-CMM, 2002 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Anatomia de Genocidio, 2007, CD (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: Asociacion Sobrevivientes, 2006 (Box 473)
    - Guatemala: CALDH, 2005 (Box 473)